It is so beyond me that this is controversial at all, but white people should not be using
the n-word.
Period.
Using the word as a white person I think just shows really intense ignorance, hatred, and
disrespect and the idea that it's like just a word or not that deep ignores the history
and power behind language.
Words freaking matter.
Every single act of hatred, violence, mass atrocity, whatever it is, it begins with language
and rhetoric that dehumanizes, divides, and incites violence.
And I fully understand that we're in a time of intense cancel culture and people are exhausted
of this constant expectation to be politically correct.
And there's definitely validity to this frustration, and liberal culture needs to give people room
to breathe, but I also think that the n-word is an exception to this.
The word became a slur during and after the transatlantic slave trade, and it was used
for centuries to demean, dehumanize, and justify the oppression of black people, and the word
carries the weight of that history.
of this, I really don't think as a white person it can be used in a humorous context.
The word has been reclaimed by black communities as an act of taking back power, which is something
I have immense respect for, but whether or not you agree with that reclaiming of the
word, you have to understand that it's fundamentally different when it's used by a black person.
It's also just not that difficult or not that much of an ask to just not say the n-word,
and I think it just shows respect, especially considering the immense amount of privilege
white people have living a life free of racial prejudice.
Just be careful with your words.
Remember that they have power.
That's all she wrote.
Bye!